# Liu, Teng-Yuan (Shuk Liu)

<u>biz.shuk@gmail.com</u>, Skype: initialshuk <u>Linkedin</u>, TW (886) 0902-398-163

Summary last updated: 2021-05-24

Full-Stack engineer aim services on the internet, mostly worked on back-end and experienced in web app, game development, analysis, AWS, CI/CD, and Agile methodology. Working on Linux(Ubuntu) or Mac and having deep understanding of VCS. Designing scalable system with higher availability is part of my job and analyzing pros and cons of technique depends on resources, also knowing concepts/layers/patterns well.

## **Skills**

Certificate: AWS - Solution Architect - associate (2018/08), TOEIC: 830(2019/01)

Language: Golang, Java (Spring Boot, MVC, Batch, Data), js(Reactjs, Redux), AWS(TF CF), Bash, SQL PHP, Perl, HTML5/CSS (SASS).

Server as a admin: Linux, Git, Nginx, Docker, Jenkins, Apache HTTP

Server as a user: Mysql(schema design), ElasticSearch, Gitlab-CI, Memcached, Rundeck, Mongo

Concept: SOLID, Design Pattern, CI/CD, MVC, Network, RWD, Cache, HA, Scalability, BDD, Agile, Lean, Scrum

## **Work Experience**

### Lead + Senior Engineer | Innova Solutions | Songshan, TW

 $2017/02 \sim$ 

Cloud solution provider. In this branch, it's BOT for Change Health Care(CHC) in U.S. healthcare industry

- Work on AWS, Golang, Java (Spring Boot, MVC, Batch, Data), ElasticSearch, Reactjs, Scrum. Small Scrum team in US. Cross-team communication, Production support
- Manage 5-8p (including QA)(3m) and lead another re-org team to form and catch up US team (permanent)
- As an interviewee for Senior and Lead level
- Integration of Enterprise Solution in CHC and architect User Engagement process(AWS Pinpoint)
- Traversed whole stack of legacy system and migrated some to new cloud architecture(not app) successfully.
- Eliminating security issues diagnosed by Fortify
- Create frameworks for Java(Lambda, Event Annotation, Spring Secret Manager plugin) Go(EventBus).
- Debug CPU consumption through jstack jstat jmap.
- Construct persistent file process architecture to process batch files and other massive processing with Async.

## Cloud Engineer | Shanghai Droi Tech Co. Ltd. | Taipei 101, TW

2015/07 - 2016/05

Internet company, 500+ people, from device hardware to backend as a cloud application solution (e.g. parse.com)

- Worked on Bash, Lua, Linux, Nginx, Docker, Jenkins, Ansible, Kubenetes, Mongo, PostgreSQL.
- Model "Backend As A Service" arch including app commit flow and integrate with Jenkins toward Kubernetes.
- End to end test framework for developers on the platform, also including syntax check, api detected, and request profiling.
- Cli tool to make linear version control, let user manage their own code simply.

### Game and BI developer | Gamesofa Inc. | Taipei, TW

2012/11 - 2015/04

Online Game company, 200 people, self-made games including Mahjong, Poker, FPS, and RPG

- Worked on LAMP, Perl, HTML5, Javascript, AngularJS, CSS, Memcache, A/B testing.
- Get requirements from PM, check the scope in each small sprint. Eventually, collaborate with QA and delivery.
- Win8 App "Godgame big two" by HTML5, integrate billing services, interact with back-end, adjust UI.
- Responsible for "Godgame Texas Hold'em" server side events and features, e.g. general friend list for multiple games, and fix bugs.
- Omaha game rule is to pick in two sets, one pick 2 in 4 and other pick 3 in 5, to combine biggest card type and compare with others people, using hash and combined with card type probability to reduce the performance issue.
- Developed survey system and deploy to different region to solve global location latency issue ,and customized options for ordered sequential options avoiding making useless data.
- User analyzing system showing user retention rate, payment and activated situations with selected group. It's easy for product manager and marketing specialist. And we may do some A/B testing for groups of user.
- Refactor and maintain existing systems, customer service system.

#### Web developer | National Central University | Jongli, Taiwan

2010/03-2011/06

Setup LAMP websites, bypass library system for ebook search, saving \$20000 at least and maintaining fee

## **Education**

- M.S. in CS, National Central University, Jongli , Taiwan, 2009.09-2011.06, June. (Java, PHP)
- B.S. in CS, National Dong-Hua University, Hualien, Taiwan, 2004.09-2009.06, Jan. (C, C++, PHP)